<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Michelle's [uncreative adjective] Blog</title>
    <link href="http://michtran.ca/blog//atom.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://michtran.ca/blog/" />
    <id>http://michtran.ca/blog//atom.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>Michelle Tran</name>
        <email>email@michtran.ca</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>Retrospective on 2018</title>
    <link href="http://michtran.ca/blog//blog/posts/2019-01-01-New-Year.html" />
    <id>http://michtran.ca/blog//blog/posts/2019-01-01-New-Year.html</id>
    <published>2019-01-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info">
<em>Posted on January  1, 2019</em>
    
</div>

<p>This was both an exciting year, and also luckily not too eventful (ie, no more health incident).</p>
<p>I started off the year with a trip to Vietnam and Hong Kong. We went with family, and the experience made me reconsider staying in Berlin.</p>
<p>I went to Malaga for a work trip in April. It was quite nice, but also too early in the year to enjoy lying on the beach.</p>
<p>In June, we travelled to Ireland and did a road trip around the whole island. It was very beautiful and I did quite a few paintings. I found the relaxed nature of the trip much more conducive for painting.</p>
<p>We went to Poland in July to visit family. On our way back, we also passed by Malbork, Toruń, and Bydgoszcz.</p>
<p>I went to Europython in Edinburgh in July. I enjoyed it more than other conferences because I was meeting up with collegues. I also went to Pycon Canada in November. It was also alright because I was not creeped out (unlike the meetups/conferences I’ve been to in Berlin). I think Berlin was a particular bad case, as I never had problems in Seattle or London either.</p>
<p>I went to Venice and Florence in August. It was a very nice trip; both were touristy cities, but the weather was exceptional. I went with my brother, so it was a nice sibling bonding time. It was also the first trip I’ve been where I didn’t plan things out in details, and so we ended up sitting at cafes sipping coffee or wine for hours. I think I really enjoy this form of travel, and maybe can do more of this in the future.</p>
<p>I also made the decision to resign at the company I was working at in August. It was difficult, but I think it was the correct decision. I definitely had a major sense of relief after I resigned.</p>
<p>Soon after I resigned, I also got offered a new job in Toronto.</p>
<p>I moved back to Toronto at the end of October. So we had the rest of the summer in Berlin. It was a beautiful dry summer, and we spent it eating icecream in the park. It’s still too early to tell if I regret the decision. I think Berlin will always have a place in my heart, but seeing family and friends every few weeks is a definite plus.</p>
<p>Before returning to Toronto, we spent a week on the Azores. It was a relaxing holiday; we ate a lot of steak and dipped in many hotsprings.</p>
<p>I suspect that we will travel less now that we’re back in Canada. I’ve got half the amount of vacation days as my previous company. Also, adjusting to a non-remote work environment wasn’t too difficult. However, I definitely miss the freedom of working from home.</p>
<p>In terms of goals for this year, I think I want to do more with art and also more for my career.</p>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Why I'm Leaving Berlin</title>
    <link href="http://michtran.ca/blog//blog/posts/2018-09-06-on_leaving_berlin.html" />
    <id>http://michtran.ca/blog//blog/posts/2018-09-06-on_leaving_berlin.html</id>
    <published>2018-09-06T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-09-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info">
<em>Posted on September  6, 2018</em>
    
</div>

<p>I’m rather sad about it still. But my time in Berlin did not go as expected.</p>
<p>In theory, the city is perfect for me; nice pace of life, city of artists, lots of awesome parks, environmentally conscious, can live without a car and the non-Anglo sense of civic responsibilities (ie. city actually cares and have done something about affordable rent, and the numerous refugee programs across the city). In my 2.5 years here, I really struggled with fitting into Berlin.</p>
<p>There are a few barriers which I can only fault myself. For instance, my lack of conversational German made the parts of the city I wanted to experience, inaccessible. In retrospect, perhaps I should’ve tried harder, continued to take classes and go out more often to make new friends. To be fair, I also struggled to go out and meet people in London and Seattle as well; everyone I became friends with were work colleagues. So the other mistake was perhaps to work for a remote company while living here.</p>
<p>Berlin is awesome in the summer, but I can’t stand the rest of the year. It is cold, wet and the sun barely exists (rises at 9, sets at 15 in the winter, and likely to be cloudy and rainy). I bought myself a daylight lamp which helps. However, 3/4 of the year is crap for that 2-3 months of really great summer, which doesn’t feel like a good deal.</p>
<p>However, the most common reason I give people, which is probably also the truest reason for returning to Toronto is family and friends. I can’t just move my family over to Berlin (although I think their lives will improve if they did), nor do I think they want to leave behind their established life in Toronto. On top of that, Berlin lacks the cultural connections that my family is familiar with. There’s at least a relatively large Chinese-Vietnamese community in Toronto In Berlin, there was maybe one other person in the block that I live in looks to be of non-European origin (probably Vietnamese). Compared to many European cities, Berlin is probably very multicultural. However, compared to Toronto, it’s just not.</p>
<p>Ultimately, after living in so many cities, eventually everything falls into an equilibrium where it no longer matters that it’s <em>that</em> particular city. I suspect going back to Toronto, I might initially indulge in what I enjoy about it and occasionally rage about the lack of good transit access, but it will reach a point where I don’t notice it anymore and it just becomes another city. For instance, I live near parks in Berlin, but I’ve noticed that I’ve stopped going this summer; or I’ve stopped drinking as much cheap beer as when I first moved here. Things will stop being novel, and annoyances will just be another fact of life.</p>
<p>In the end, it’s the family, friends and job that matters. I’m really sad to be leaving, but what I want in my life now cannot be given to me outside of Toronto.</p>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>On Reading Physical Books</title>
    <link href="http://michtran.ca/blog//blog/posts/2018-03-12-reading_physical_books.html" />
    <id>http://michtran.ca/blog//blog/posts/2018-03-12-reading_physical_books.html</id>
    <published>2018-03-12T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-03-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="info">
<em>Posted on March 12, 2018</em>
    
</div>

<p>I’ve recently bought myself a physical copy of <em>The Order of Things</em> by Michel Foucault. I don’t usually keep physical copies of books because I move often and it is not very economical to continually ship them with me when I move. However, I have been avoiding purchasing things off Amazon recently and luckily found a physical copy of this book in a local bookshop. So I purchased it.</p>
<p>There is a sort of romance to holding a physical book that you don’t get with an e-reader. There is the tactile nature of the book itself, the physical movement of turning a page and flipping through the sections. Sometimes I like to skip to the spoilers at the end, or flip back to find the moment of foreshadow. Then there’s also the imagery of the person sitting by the window in a coffee shop, with their fingers grazing the page while their eyes look out to reflect on the passage that they’ve just read. One can try to imagine these scenarios with an e-reader, but the artistry of the scene pales in comparison.</p>
<p>So being the first physical book I’ve picked up in over a year, I found myself dissatisfied with the experience. For instance, the binding of the book made it uncomfortable to read the book in bed, where my lamp shines at an angle from the side so that the words near the margin will inevitably end up in shadow. Also, I like to read while lying down, and although my book is not <em>very</em> heavy, my forearms will eventually feel the strain of holding the weight of the book and hands in the same overhead position. Any attempt to turn myself to lay the book on its side will mean that part of the book will be in unwanted shadows.</p>
<p>Then there’s also the constant distraction in the back of my mind about whether or not the book is <em>good</em> enough that I will want to keep it on my next move: <em>Will this book be a good reference in the future? How many books should I ship back?</em> Or even: <em>Should I just get an e-book copy of this after I’m done?</em></p>
<p>And lastly, there’s also the guilt that I’m just accumulating <em>junk</em>. After I purchase an e-book, it has no <em>presence</em>, but with a physical book, it literally <em>weighs</em> me down. An e-book is an <em>experience</em>, but a physical book is just more <em>stuff</em>.</p>
<p>Admittedly, I still enjoy being able to flip back easily to scan through old passages, especially since <em>The Order of Things</em> is a particularly dense read. However, I’m finding that I’ve gone <em>technological</em> and there’s no coming back.</p>
]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
